He wasn't greedy
it's like he knew when to give up
if he'd been more aggressive
he could've been president
maybe even lived longer
with him gone, though
my life is a lot easier
I sometimes feel guilty that
he's not here to share the fun
everything was half measures
his job, the family
well, he had his fun
so cheers
I saw you two going to play golf
did you?
My husband really liked Hiroshi
very much
you were so honest and modest
just a country boy
your father died young
didn't he, Hiroshi?
Yes, I was five, so I don't remember
what he looked like
I rather envy you
my father lived to 98 years old
we got sick of the sight of each other
Mitsuru, have you fed them?
Not yet?
You want to feed them with daddy?
I'll help you
excuse us
it's a silly hobby
keeping chickens like that
as he said himself
he's a country boy
Mitsuru, here
let me in there
look, a freshly laid egg
it's spring, that's when they
lay a lot of eggs
little chicks will hatch
chicks?
Then they'll grow up and lay more eggs
they're nice and warm
I've never chanted sutras
to hens before
a little souvenir for you
they're delicious
not like supermarket eggs
well, thank you very much
I'll wrap them for you
thank you
I've stayed far too long
I really must go now
we appreciate your prayers
why don't we sing a song for
father in heaven?
When I first put to sea
as a sailor man
the mast was smashed
and the sails all torn
mighty waves washed over
the wooden deck
but I'll not be troubled
if it's here that I die
awaiting me is my
lovely bride
and my beloved parents
who await me still
more pills?
Do you think I should go and
see a psychiatrist
trouble sleeping again?
No, not really
I dreamed I was pregnant
that's not funny
it was just a dream
good morning
you think too much
I'd better get going
take care
see you later
you're up early today
come on, let's go and see
your father off
it's good buy
trust me, please
I beg your pardon?
Something less risky?
Maybe convertible debentures?
Oh, really?
My sales are way down
I need your business
you could help me out...
I see
certainly
I'll set it up for you
thank you. Bye
I made that man a millionaire!
The buyers are getting a lot smarter
no, our company is losing
their trust
hello?
Nirazaki from Nippo security
yes, I've got an excellent buy for you
Moodys are downgrading us
it'll be in the newspapers soon
that's the end of our company
it'll take more than that
are you dreaming?
They're already drafting articles
about our bankruptcy
your brain only works at the office
do you ever talk to outsiders?
No point in competing at a
company that's going down the tubes
I don't think it'll fail
you're living the past
even banks are failing
look, we're in the same
financial sector
in this condition, who's going
to buy our recommendations?
Everyone's clawing like crazy
to get out
central bank won't intervene
better start practicing crowd control
how's Mizuho?
What a question
she's from a good family
she relies on you, so get it together
why should you care?
To tell the truth
I've found a new job
that was quick
no, you're just too slow
what about your clients?
In days we'll be out in the street
no time for them
think about your future
no, I really mean it
is that you, Hiroshi?
Is your name Hiroshi?
Yes...
what can I do for you?
I knew it was you!
You remember me?
You don't, do you?
I guess I can't blame you
you were only five at the time
but I can still see traces of
you as a boy
you're looking good
I've been so eager to see you
I really missed you
sorry
I don't recall you
I'm Sasaichi Hamaguchi!
Don't you recognize your own
father's name?
My father?!
My father died a long time ago
Kimiyo told you that, eh?
I was wrong to
abandon you like that
I often thought of
coming back to see you
just never found the chance
what was your name again?
Sasaichi Hamaguchi
I remember mother did tell me that
I searched everywhere and now
I've found you. Good!
Can you put me up tonight?
Look, it's all so sudden
I can hardly believe it
I don't blame you
I've got so much to tell you
you'll soon come around
let's have a heart to heart
just you and me, son
sure...
it's strange, he was supposed
to have died ages ago
that's what they said when
you got married
I'll go that
I want to hear, too
you were about 5 years old
at the time
my business went bust
and I was heavily in debt
to stop them getting
the money from Kimiyo,
we got a divorce
these days I sell fishing gear
down in Amasaki
as I got older, I began to
worry about you
how did you find out
where I live?
Your mother had told
her parents about you
how you graduated and
married into a good family
I had a private detective
search for you
that was five years ago
five years ago?
So you've know all this time?
I was happy to hear you
were alive and doing well
why didn't you contact me then?
Knowing you were doing well
was enough for me
I'll get you a glass
ice, too
so I closed down my shop
I came to Tokyo
I was eager to see you
it'll be here a week
can I stay till then?
Daddy
Mizuho come get him
and you get into bed
got a son, have you?
This is just too much
never thought I'd be sitting
here drinking with my boy
delicious
is he staying the night?
I can hardly throw him
out into the street
is he really your father?
You told me he was dead
that's what I thought
but one thing...
mother sometimes changed her story
after she'd had a drink
what do you mean?
He is your father, isn't he?
I really don't know
you don't know?
Then what should I do?
Again, I don't know
I have trouble comprehending
he's my father
I need time to think it over
I can't believe it!
For me?
Thank you!
Miss me?
Of course I did
it's getting harder to get
a full truckload
of course he's not your father!
Then who is he?
Ignore him
he's just there to sponge off you
my bill
thank you
he'll stay forever if you let him
get rid of him
he's a practical man
not like Hiroshi
is he really Hiroshi's father?
I should ask him to repair
the sliding door
watch out for the thorns
my hands can take it
at this time of year the branches
are very flexible
cut them now and they'll shoot
new branches and buds
bantams, aren't they?
No, they're hens
Hiroshi keeps them?
He hated them when he was a kid
why is he suddenly so eager
to see you now?
I heard he was shacked up
with a woman in Amasaki
you knew all along?
The folks in my hometown...
were kind enough to tell me
so... he really is my father
looks like he believes you're
his son, too
what does that mean?
Just forget it
have nothing to do with him
mother, Shige should leave
you've lost weight
are you eating properly?
Of course I am
wake up!
Shige!
It's time to head out
thanks for reminding me
take care
look...
he was absolutely hopeless
he took half measures
he was a quitter
he started out as a deckhand
on a freighter
then he became an auto-mechanic
after that he borrowed money
to buy a fishing boat
he never stuck to any one thing
for very long
he was heavily in debt
he wanted to use my money
so I divorced him
then he went missing
the man was a
loud-mouthed braggart
a woman chaser and
a big spender
no redeeming virtues at all
so you killed him off and
told me he died?
Forget that
don't get involved with him
he'll only create problems with
Mizuho and her mother
but if he is my father
I can't just ignore him
you should have called me first
how's Mitsuru? I really miss him
he must be getting big
hi there, how is it?
Hello little brother
what brings you here?
Want a beer?
No thanks. I must go
two glasses
you really should see more
of your mother
don't leave everything to us
sorry, I'm just so busy
sit down
what's the news at work?
The newspaper say your
company's going under
well...
times are tough
during the bubble economy
you swaggered about
you're not swaggering now
he'll be fine once the economy picks up
okay, I'll see you later
but you don't have to worry, do you?
You married into a wealthy family
right. See you later
get rid of him as soon as possible
if you don't, it'll only lead to problems
begone ye devils!
What did he want?
I've no idea
but it sounded important
why don't you put your foot down?
He should share in taking care of mom
the diner can't last for much longer
not so fast
I'm working on the franchise deal now
begone de devils!
Grandpa!
Are you okay, grandpa?
You must be exhausted
have a drink
stop it, Mitsuru
that's enough
it's over
welcome home
what's going on here?
Father was playing with Mitsuru
he's been ever so helpful today
he repaired the leaking bathtub
and the door doesn't squeak any more
he's been wonderful
come on, Hiroshi
let's have a drink
two, six, two
foul
it sure is
yours are all fouls
six, one, six
six, six, one
do you know what he's
teaching Mitsuru?
Gambling! It's embarrassing enough
that he turned up
I want him out of here
so why not tell him?
What does Hiroshi say?
He's always home late
however late, you must talk this out
the man reeks of alcohol
Mitsuru, how about
we have chicken stew for dinner?
I already ate
look, I've tried to do my best
for your father
but I'm at my limit
he taught Mitsuru how to
play craps
that's no big deal
and your hen!
Your hen...
...is fried chicken
welcome home
you taught Mitsuru to gamble
sit down
you remember I taught you craps?
You've been here 10 days now
just a couple more days
that's no end to that
is there?
Can you be packed and out
by tomorrow?
I'll throw in bullet-train tickets, too
who in hell do you think I am?
I am your father!
Suddenly?
After 30 years of neglect?
So what?
A father is always a father!
Mother and I both...
we don't need you
you're the only decent soul
in this house
you're too good for him
you suddenly turn up...
kill my hen...
what's that?
My hen...
I got you!
I thought you had the day off?
Is mother going out today?
Yes, to some exhibition
what?
I'll talk to him again tonight
when will the chicks be born
daddy?
Well...
what's up?
That's the limit!
He's peeping on me!
Peeping?
What are you up to?
I'm sorry!
I... wasn't thinking
forgive me
what on earth do you think
you're doing?
Now get out!
Don't be so angry
okay
take care
that was fun
"no comment"
such a pretty girl, that Joanna
what'll we do next?
Let's take Joanna and her friend
to another bar
that tough guy
too much of a hassle
better be getting home, then
yes, I guess so
the company I got a job with...
...needs a few more staff
why don't you apply?
I can't imagine getting another job
you can
we can do anything
we're gamblers by profession
don't you get tired of it?
Unlike you, I can't change
so suddenly
well, we're not getting any younger
getting old, are we?
You look as young as the day
you started
that's because you see me
every day
I guess so
I don't feel like going home
let's have some noodles
that sounds good
where's the noodle shop?
Must be one close by
mother!
What are you saying?
You know those tramps in the park?
I saw Hiroshi's father there
never
he went back home
didn't he?
Oh no!
What shall we do?
It is him, isn't it?
Really?
Are you sure it was him?
Yes, I made doubly sure
good grief!
What's he up to?
How should I know?
Hey, Hiroshi!
What's this?
Whose bike is that?
Stupid old fool!
What's this?
Good
and this?
Very good
what's this?
Taful
no. It's a table
like this table here
now practice your ABC's out loud
I'm going shopping
Alright, dear
hey, honey!
You after something?
We'll just ignore him
what if something happens?
If he freezes to death
it'll be our fault
he's just trying to make us
feel sorry for him
he's a lot more cunning than
you think
it's really sad
long-lost one day
homeless the next
he's still your father
that's why I don't care
let him stew
maybe he doesn't have a home
to go back to
that's not our problem
he'd only cause trouble here
I've heard enough
it's so sad
what?
Mizuho!
Are you okay?
Your inhaler
these pills work better
don't take too many
they make me light-headed
the poor man...
come on
you'd better lie down
what is it?
It's just so funny!
Your face looks so funny!
Stop it
stop laughing
stop it
Mizuho!
Stop it now
don't laugh!
I'm sorry
why can't you be kind?
Why did you have to hit me?
Don't cry, Mizuho
hey you, foreigner!
Piss off back to your own country!
You stink!
Piss off!
What's your problem?
You like that do you?
You bum!
Get yourself a bloody job!
Hey! That's enough!
What the hell?
You're on their side?
You don't want trouble
you have a family, right?
Stop fighting!
You disgust me!
Look what you've done
what the hell is your problem?
You're drunk, right?
Look at 'em
damn useless vagrants!
So what?
What gives you the right?
You're one of us
why take their side?
Bravery fortified by alcohol
you should be ashamed!
You should be!
Damned bums
piss off back to Shinjuku!
Use this
goddamn it!
Let's go
come on
okay
guys, grab my stuff
he's my son
you guys take care
what if he decides to
stay here permanently?
I shudder at the thought
father!
Your pajamas
I'll leave them here
thank you
"fools cut cherry
only idiots don't cut plum"
without a man it becomes
a jungle
Mitsuru, I'm not finished!
Grandpa, come and look
what is it?
Listen, they're chirping
they are, too
they're little chicks
baby chicks have hatched!
They're so cute
I can't believe it
what?
They hatched, you say?
Double little chicks!
Not "double"
we say "two chicks"
aren't they sweet!
We did it!
We did, daddy!
Mitsuru, you're just like your dad
look at them eating
let's make a new pen
separate them from the bantams
there'll be lots more
we'll need wire netting
let's get to it, then
I'll take a day off
more chickens?
Are they serious?
Like father, like son
see how their posture's the same?
Hiroshi, try some of this
thank you, mother
daddy the chicks are dead
poor little things
dead, are they?
How come?
They fell into the water
I just saw them earlier
the bowl's too deep
poor things!
They've hardly drawn breath
don't worry
plenty more where they came from
Nippo securities files for protection
what's up?
I'm going to the office
don't make anything
Mr. President... Mr. President
he didn't even mention it?
What does "file for protection" mean?
Are you serious?
It means that they're bankrupt
he still seems to get his salary
he never tells you anything
even something as important as this
he doesn't want us to worry
not worry? When his company's
going out of business?
Excuse me!
Anyone here?
Hello in there!
I'm looking for Hamaguchi
Sasaichi Hamaguchi
Hiroshi's father?
He came to Tokyo to visit his son
and I haven't heard from him since
and who are you?
I'm Yaeko Togashi
in here
please, sit down
today's racing pick...
"just guy"
hey, I'll change my ways
so please come back home
I'm sorry I said you should
earn your keep at your age
I'm here to apologize
I'm very sorry
she's come all this way
haven't you?
You reckon?
How wonderful to have someone
to share your twilight years
I'll look after him
we've been together 15 years
like glue
you can do as you like
you can drink
I won't complain any more
I know what you're up to
you insured me to the hilt
then put me to work
you're trying to kill me off
you have no inkling of
my feelings
you've been gone a month
I've realized how much I miss you
come back!
I miss you
you can hardly refuse
such an appeal...
sweet words mask much
she turned me into an alcoholic
to get me on the
slab that much quicker
meanwhile, she pockets the insurance
it's enough to make the booze
stick in your throat
I'm busy
I understand
Alright then
you want your son to take care of you
then stay here
let me know when he dies
I'll burn incense for him
this is ridiculous...
take good care of him
I gave my life to you
I deserve the insurance!
Good riddance!
That's the end of that
sorry for the bother
what a surprise!
Who was that woman?
He's back there again?
How can I ever apologize?
Yes, of course
I'll be there tonight
Alright, see you then
mother, are you going out tonight?
Yes, I have some errands
we wanted to talk to you about
redistributing the property
I haven't changed my mind
it's me who set up and
ran this shop
you can take over when I receive
what we agreed to
then you can change it to a
pinball parlor or a motel
you can do as you please
he certainly has a nerve
that man
I told Hiroshi that he had died
he's only brought trouble
for Mizuho and Hiroshi
to think he was my husband of
30 years ago,
I could sink through the floor
please
hello, Hiroshi
what brings you here?
Leave everything to me
father, if you don't mind
mother wants to talk to you
what?
Are you Kimiyo?
You are, aren't you?
Don't look at me like that
long time no see, Sasaichi
this is a surprise
I'm dumbfounded
you've gotten old
there's something that I must tell you
I realize that you're not happy
with this arrangement
but all I've got left is Hiroshi
he's my only son, he is
I am sorry
but you're really not Hiroshi's father
there's no blood link at all
you're complete strangers
wait...
mother!
But he really isn't your father
Minoru Kataoka is
what did you say?
A year before Hiroshi was born
that tuna fisherman, Kaikichi
asked you to work for him
you went off to Australia
didn't you?
During those 6 months
that you were away...
I fell pregnant with
Minoru's child
I did a good job of fooling you
but the truth is that Hiroshi
is really Minoru's son
there were rumors
you could have heard about it
what does that make me?
You needn't worry
Minoru is a man I longed for
when I was young
so kind, a real hunk and a leader
of the young men's association
so...
...so that's the story
I'm sorry to upset you
but that's what happened
so that's what happened?
So, Minoru is...
my husband passed away
3 years ago
I really have no choice
if you take Hiroshi
what's left for me?
He's all I have left
okay, I understand
well I can't stay here
can I?
Hiroshi, I'm sorry about all this
well, there's no hurry
you can stay longer
we've no objections
now I know the facts
I have to go
you just forget all about me
thanks for everything
father!
Ambulance!
Call an ambulance!
Come in
why did you wait until
he was critical?
Is it that bad?
It's terminal cirrhosis
with extreme complications
if he has another attack
he could die
I doubt he'll pull through
I understand
I appreciate it, doctor
mom, the hen has laid more eggs!
Really?
We'll take them to grandpa
will they make him better?
Yes
really?
Yes, dear
put them in the basket
here
freshly laid
just this morning
put them over there
certainly
I brought some radish relish
you like it, don't you?
And some soup, too
don't worry about me
it wasn't much trouble
grandpa, a picture for you
they're just leftovers
hang it up there
leaving your washing out
I want you to do me a favor
what is it?
I'd like some sake
no, you can't
a small bottle will do
I can't do that
the doctor will be furious and
after all, this is a hospital
so just forget all about drinking!
Even if he isn't your real father
he took care of you as a boy
so let's do what we can for him
but that costs money
I have savings
I can pay the hospital bill
you've never lacked for anything
maybe so
but please
you've never known hardship
morning has broken
dawn has come
no matter what they say
a man needs a drink
that's the truth
hearts bursting with pride...
the pride of men who go to sea
okay, cut it out!
The staff are furious with you
they'll kick you out
if you don't stop now
we'd better go
you take care of yourself
cover up
I was but a lad of fourteen years
when first I put to sea as
a sailor man
the first time our ship cleared the port
the mast was smashed and
the sails all torn
mighty waves washed over
the wooden deck
but I'll not be troubled
if it's here that I die
that song...
it's our song, lad
when first I put to sea as
a sailor man
the mast was smashed and
the sails all torn
mighty waves washed over
the wooden deck
but I'll not be troubled
if it's here that I die
awaiting me is my lovely bride
and my parents
more important to me
Neptune beckons me...
I really am your son after all
as Kimiyo says
I might be infertile
offer up prayers
and make your vows
to Neptune
the king of all seas
mighty Neptune
will you quieten the storm?
For just a little while
for just a little while
I wonder how he is?
Well...
I visited the hospital today
but he was fast asleep
he's like that recently
the man's nuisance whether
he's sick or well
it's too bad
what are you doing?
Shall I make a snack?
Listen...
look...
I must apologize to you
what for?
The company's restructuring plan
was rejected
that means they're bankrupt
you only ever give results
it was all so sudden
you never discuss anything
you never have
you turned your back on
your own father
selfishly thinking
only you've suffered
maybe you're right
did I really enjoy my work?
There'll be no final payment
I don't know what to do
hello, Nirazaki residence
it's the hospital!
Your father's dying!
Take the call
we should've contacted you earlier
I never knew if he wanted to
live or not
my sincere regrets
let's go
let's go home
little chicks!
This is incredible!
He said he would try to hatch them
and he did it!
He didn't eat those eggs
he nurtured them
who would ever have imagined?
Father...
spreading his ashes, how sad
I bet he's happy
he loved a ceremony
I wonder...
I never saw the body
so I keep expecting him to turn up
if he did, would you insure him again?
Don't say that!
I was good to him
it was such a short time...
you seem to be getting younger
really?
Do you think so?
Shall we begin?
I suppose we must
will normal funerary prayers do?
Anything, I suppose
great god of compassion...
ashes to ashes
dust to dust
doesn't Hiroshi take after him?
You lied, didn't you?
I'll keep a piece of him
which bone was it?
I'll have to find a new job
don't worry
life will go on
you know, I'm quite strong
even so
it's a long haul...
Mitsuru!
You've got a strong mother!